<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="F4508815-F21A-44D6-808D-A838FFEEC6D1">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20120629" date="2012-06-29 07:24:52 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Windy Pass Dirt Bike Ride: Where&#x2019;s Matt??&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Friday, July 9, 2010&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Today Chase (Chaser on MotoUtah), Matt (not on MotoUtah), and I rode the Windy Pass trail for the first time. We started at the equestrian parking lot a mile past Big Springs Park up South Fork off Provo Canyon. The GPS track is plotted on a Google Map &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="http://nanomicro.byu.edu/~nordin/Maps/100709a-South%20Fork%20&amp;%20Windy%20Pass,%20Matt%20&amp;%20Chase.html"&gt;at this link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;.&#xD;&#xD;Here are Chase (left) and Matt (right) at the junction of Trails 058 and 057:&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;And here is the sign board:&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;We hung a left at the junction to stay on Trail 058 going up to Windy Pass. Here&#x2019;s Chase doing the last little climb up to the pass:&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;I was surprised that Matt was no where to be seen. Chase let me know that Matt had inadvertently layed over his bike on a rocky uphill section and it happened to drop just right so that the end of the shift lever broke off. He said Matt was stuck in 1st gear and was going to go back to the truck. Despite suffering our first bike casualty, Chase and I pressed on. &#xD;&#xD;Here is Chase just after the steep, loose, rocky switchbacks that you come to right after Windy Pass:&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;A little farther as we stopped for a few minutes I was very surprised to hear my cell phone ring. On the off chance that it might be Matt I decided to go through the hassle of taking my camelbak off and getting my phone out of my camelbak. It wasn&#x2019;t Matt, but the caller thought it was pretty cool that they had caught me at 9,000 feet way in the back country above South Fork. &#xD;&#xD;After the call I got my cell phone stowed away in my camelbak, put the camelbak back on and was just about to kickstart my motor (yeah, I don&#x2019;t have e-start) when I heard my phone go off again. Because it might have been Matt, I went through the whole process again of taking off my camelbak and fishing my phone out. Turns out it wasn&#x2019;t Matt. &#xD;&#xD;By the time I was all put back together so we could start riding again we found that the flies were out in force and had located us. Boy, were they annoying! Lots of big black ones that for some reason thought we were worth buzzing around and landing on. It was sure nice to get moving again.&#xD;&#xD;Chase and I went most of the way to the end of 058 &amp; turned around about where Gig &amp; I had gotten to a few weeks ago when we tried to do the trail in the reverse direction but were stopped by deadfall.&#xD;&#xD;Here&#x2019;s Chase on the ride back:&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;Just after this picture was taken a thunderstorm rolled in and we got soaked while booking down the trail. It was really weird going from hot and sweaty to cold and wet. Quite refreshing though. Fortunately, the rain didn&#x2019;t last long and we made it out from under the storm and back into the sunshine.&#xD;&#xD;When we got back to the truck we were surprised to find no sign of Matt or his bike. Instead, we found a whole bunch of golf balls (~30) on the ground right by my truck. We thought, &#x201C;Hmm, if this is a message from Matt, we have no idea what it&#x2019;s supposed to tell us!&#x2019;&#x2019;  We wondered if Matt had taken a wrong turn and wasn&#x2019;t able to make it to the truck. This was his first time in this area so it was conceivable that he&#x2019;d made a wrong turn on the trails.&#xD;&#xD;Looking around some more, we found a couple of plastic juice containers in the back of my truck that contained gas &amp; premix. Matt usually carries this in his backpack for long rides (hence his nickname, &#x201C;Molotov Matt&#x201D;) since his gas tank isn&#x2019;t very big so his bike only has about a 25 mile range (Matt rides a 1994 YZ250&#x2014;poor student&#x2019;s bike). This seemed to indicate that maybe Matt had made it to the truck after all. But we couldn&#x2019;t remember if he&#x2019;d been carrying these particular bottles or not so it still wasn&#x2019;t clear. &#xD;&#xD;Chase and I were in a quandary. It was after 5:00 pm and we had no idea if Matt had made it to the truck, was out on a trail somewhere due to a wrong turn or perhaps even joyriding and had broken down, or maybe had gotten someone to take him and his bike back to my house where his truck was. His cell phone was locked in my truck so there was no way to contact him. &#xD;&#xD;Chase had a dinner appointment and needed to leave. I told him to go ahead and I would search the Big Spring trails to see if maybe Matt was out there. When I got to the start of Trail 058 where it intersects with the trail to Big Spring, I noticed a faint motorcycle tire track heading toward Big Spring. It was clear that it had rained after the track was made, and there were fresh mountain bike tracks on top of them.&#xD;&#xD;Here&#x2019;s part of the trail:&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;I felt like an old time animal tracker trying to follow the motorcycle tire tracks through the various trail intersections. In the end they led me on Trail 059 up past Big Spring. At that point I caught a lucky break. I ran into a young lady with a dog and she had seen a motorcycle guy who was broken down and could only coast downhill. She pointed me back toward Big Spring as the direction the other guy had taken. I kept going downhill at each trail intersection and found Matt at the campground above Big Spring park. There was a father/son campout going on and one of the father&#x2019;s used to be a dirt bike mechanic and was able to help Matt get his bike back into working order. I rode up just as they finished.&#xD;&#xD;So here&#x2019;s what happened to Matt. He initially made it back to the truck just fine. As he was kicking around trying to figure out how to kill several hours before we got back he noticed that there were golf balls out among the weeds in an adjacent field. Since golf balls are pricey and he golfs, enterprising person that he is he went out and found a bunch of balls and deposited them next to my truck. So, there was no intended message in the pile of golf balls&#x2014;it was just an attempt to save some money!&#xD;&#xD;At that point the flies found him. He came to the same solution we did: get on the bike and keep moving! So he went for a joy ride in 1st gear with a broken shifter. He ended up going most of the way up Trail 059 above Big Spring, making it almost to the gnarly switchbacks near the top.&#xD;&#xD;That&#x2019;s where he experienced his 2nd mechanical failure of the day. His chain came off and wadded up around his countershaft sprocket. Arghhh!&#xD;&#xD;He did the only thing he could do: turn the bike around and try to coast all the way down the mountain. However, there were some pesky uphill sections that he had to push his bike up, which was very tough. &#xD;&#xD;On one of these sections he decided to scout it on foot before pushing his bike up. As he reached the top he inadvertently surprised the young lady who I later ran into. She was hiking the trail in the opposite direction with her dog. Wearing his colorful dirt bike gear, Matt must have been quite a sight walking the trail. The dog wasn&#x2019;t impressed and nearly took a piece out of him. &#xD;&#xD;Matt eventually made it to the campground. The old dirt bike mechanic was able to help get Matt&#x2019;s chain squared away enough so that he could ride with me back to the truck.&#xD;&#xD;Now, the moral of the story: keep your cell phone with you in case you have coverage, and in case you don&#x2019;t always have a piece of paper and something to write with so you can leave a note!&#xD;&#xD;As a final comment, you could tell that the Windy Pass trail has recently had a lot of maintenance done on it&#x2014;as I understand it, by the Rocky Mountain motorcycle club. I just want to say thanks&#x2014;you guys did a great job!&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="9_Windy_Pass_Dirt_Bike_Ride__Wheres_Matt_files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="700px" height="400px"/>
</content>
