<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:iweb="http://www.apple.com/iweb" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Greg’s Blog</title>
    <link>file://localhost/Users/nordin2/Dropbox/Public/web/Greg_Nordins_Blog/Blog/Blog.html</link>
    <description>Random comments &amp;amp; photos from dirt bike and mountain bike rides...</description>
    <generator>iWeb 3.0.4</generator>
    <image>
      <url>file://localhost/Users/nordin2/Dropbox/Public/web/Greg_Nordins_Blog/Blog/Blog_files/DSCN2595.jpg</url>
      <title>Greg’s Blog</title>
      <link>file://localhost/Users/nordin2/Dropbox/Public/web/Greg_Nordins_Blog/Blog/Blog.html</link>
    </image>
    <item>
      <title>Moab 2011</title>
      <link>file://localhost/Users/nordin2/Dropbox/Public/web/Greg_Nordins_Blog/Blog/Entries/2011/5/7_Moab_2011.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">3b382111-efa4-4b08-822b-721230a6ef63</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 7 May 2011 14:19:44 -0600</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;a href=&quot;file://localhost/Users/nordin2/Dropbox/Public/web/Greg_Nordins_Blog/Blog/Entries/2011/5/7_Moab_2011_files/DSCN3570.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;file://localhost/Users/nordin2/Dropbox/Public/web/Greg_Nordins_Blog/Blog/Media/object004_1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float:left; padding-right:10px; padding-bottom:10px; width:216px; height:123px;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;This year our Moab trip was somewhat abbreviated, consisting of 3.5 days of riding, from May 4 to May 7, instead of 6 days like last year due to some scheduling conflicts with work. We also had a shifting cast of characters. Mark &amp;amp; Pat from Huntsville, Alabama were not able to make it this year because Mark broke his leg a few months ago and isn’t quite ready to go yet. While they were sorely missed, we still had a fantastic time! &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;We stayed all 4 nights of our trip in Green River rather than Moab because it was more central to the trails we wanted to ride. While there is definitely a lot more happening in Moab than Green River, the convenience more than outweighed other considerations. Besides, Green River has one of our favorite dinner stops--Rays!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;A new participant, Dave, had a helmet cam and made a video from his footage for each of the 4 days we rode. The videos are included below. If you can only watch one of them, be sure to look at Day 4 on which we rode the infamous 5 Miles of Hell trail, which was definitely a challenge!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This year I didn’t take as many pictures, but I’ve included links to some photos from Days 1 &amp;amp; 2. On Day 3 my camera began to die the same way all of my previous cameras have given up the ghost, i.e., grit in the lens mechanism which causes it to become stuck. Fortunately, it has since cleared itself. The camera has already lasted a lot longer (1.5 years) than my previous cameras (1 year at the most!) since I’ve been much more careful about protecting it from trail dust. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Below is a map with GPS tracks from each day’s ride. Day 2 (May 5) is broken up into two tracks.</description>
      <enclosure url="file://localhost/Users/nordin2/Dropbox/Public/web/Greg_Nordins_Blog/Blog/Entries/2011/5/7_Moab_2011_files/DSCN3570.jpg" length="189509" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Backcountry Skiing</title>
      <link>file://localhost/Users/nordin2/Dropbox/Public/web/Greg_Nordins_Blog/Blog/Entries/2010/11/30_Backcountry_Skiing.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">1d038d34-d670-49c9-992e-fc2b77151534</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2010 16:00:14 -0700</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;a href=&quot;file://localhost/Users/nordin2/Dropbox/Public/web/Greg_Nordins_Blog/Blog/Entries/2010/11/30_Backcountry_Skiing_files/DSCN2876.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;file://localhost/Users/nordin2/Dropbox/Public/web/Greg_Nordins_Blog/Blog/Media/object003_1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float:left; padding-right:10px; padding-bottom:10px; width:219px; height:124px;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;This morning Karl, a buddy from my department, picked me up at 6:00 am for my 2nd backcountry skiing adventure. For those who don’t know, backcountry skiing is where you put “skins” on the bottom of your skis to give you traction to climb up a mountain. Once at the top, you take the skins off, put them in your pack, and ski down. It’s a fantastic workout and let’s you get into areas of virgin powder away from the normal resorts. Our objective today was to get in a big climb before we needed to be at work.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; We drove for an hour and went up Little Cottonwood Canyon. The original plan was to climb Grizzly Gulch next to the Alta ski resort. However, the sight of a nearby ridge next to Flagstaff Mountain caused a change in plans. The snow there was simply too enticing!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;As we geared up it was COLD! The temperature was somewhere below 10 F. Here is Karl right before we started. We are going to go up the mountainside just beyond the right edge of the photo.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;As we began our ascent there were a number of other people out with the same plan as ours. We will climb to the highest point you can see to the left of the center of the photo. From this angle you can’t really tell how steep it is. It’s not too bad at this point, but gets quite a bit steeper a little higher up.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Here is Karl.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The sun is slowly making its way above the mountains behind us. This is a view to the west. Note the ski tracks on the mountainside.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Here’s another view during the climb. With the sun up it got pretty warm--at least in the 20’s!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Looking down toward Alta.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Another view during the climb.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;After an hour and 45 minutes we made it to the top of the ridge, having climbed 1,650 feet.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Karl&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Me&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;And now for some of the views from the top. It was spectacular! To the north we could look into Big Cottonwood Canyon. Here is looking to the west down Little Cottonwood Canyon.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Looking to the southeast. You can see Alta at the bottom of the canyon.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Now we’re all set to go down. Here’s a look beyond Karl’s skis at the slope we are about to descend.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Video of Karl coming down. It’s difficult to see how steep it is in the video since we’re looking straight uphill.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;And one of me:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Looking back on our ski tracks.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Now we are most of the way down. Looking up at what we just skied:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;We made it back to the car in a little under 2.5 hours. View from the car: &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Bottom line: backcountry skiing is great! It will definitely be one of my major winter activities. In addition to the excellent skiing in deep powder, the workout is fantastic. My heart rate monitor said I had an average heart rate of 142 beats per minute and burned 1,750 calories. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The cool thing is that there is so much country in the mountains around here to explore. I can’t wait!</description>
      <enclosure url="file://localhost/Users/nordin2/Dropbox/Public/web/Greg_Nordins_Blog/Blog/Entries/2010/11/30_Backcountry_Skiing_files/DSCN2876.jpg" length="178195" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What, No Dust??</title>
      <link>file://localhost/Users/nordin2/Dropbox/Public/web/Greg_Nordins_Blog/Blog/Entries/2010/10/30_What,_No_Dust.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">05d575b1-4e59-4ae8-a3b4-b909a18d4976</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2010 21:33:32 -0600</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;a href=&quot;file://localhost/Users/nordin2/Dropbox/Public/web/Greg_Nordins_Blog/Blog/Entries/2010/10/30_What,_No_Dust_files/DSCN2691_1.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;file://localhost/Users/nordin2/Dropbox/Public/web/Greg_Nordins_Blog/Blog/Media/object002_1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float:left; padding-right:10px; padding-bottom:10px; width:216px; height:123px;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Aaron and I did another desert race today, this time in Indianola which is off Hwy 89 on the way to Manti. Google map of my GPS track is &lt;a href=&quot;http://nanomicro.byu.edu/~nordin/Maps/2010-10-30%20RACE-Indianola%20with%20Aaron.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;What a great race! Definitely the funnest course I have ridden. Although it now seems somewhat unnatural, it was a very nice change to not have any dust or whoops! A big thanks to the Sageriders Motorcycle Club who put it on, and especially to the landowner for permitting us to have the race on his land!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Turn-off:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Sign ups:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This was my son Aaron’s second race. We didn’t arrive until about 10:20. Fortunately sign-ups were still being processed since I wasn’t early enough to register us by mail. Unloading the truck and getting ready:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Pit row:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The costumes were great. I particularly enjoyed these at the riders meeting:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;I’m pretty sure I saw a part of the white bride’s outfit later out on the trail. I guess it’s not exactly a practical dirt bike outfit!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Dave at the rider’s meeting (thanks for posting the video—it’s great!):&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Aaron at the starting line:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Experts starting line:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Aaron:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Well, that’s all I got before the race. Now on to the report…&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;As I loaded up the truck at home in the morning I noticed that I only had one set of elbow guards. I realized that I must have lent Aaron’s set to a friend a few weeks ago when I was teaching my friend and his 15 year old son how to ride their just-purchased dirt bikes. Since we didn’t have 2 sets of elbow guards, Aaron and I split the set we had and I put my one guard on my right elbow. I should have known the folly of making such a choice. Of course the only time I went down during the race I low-sided in a lefthand corner (3rd loop in the tight trees) and landed on the unprotected elbow. Oh well, I’m sure the swelling will subside soon!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;After the start I was ahead of Aaron, but he passed me in the grass track section. A few other guys got around too. I really wanted to pull in behind my son and see if I could stay up with him so I eventually picked them off until I was right behind him. Someone else passed me on the off-camber slick rocky section on the side of the mountain and then we got to the steep uphill. I could see Aaron up ahead and that he’d lost momentum and was trying to avoid stalling. That’s when I hit the hill and had to concentrate. Unfortunately, the concentration didn’t do much good and I stalled my bike. That’s when I lost Aaron and didn’t see him again the rest of the race. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Coming into the grass track section at the end of the first loop there was a KTM 2 stroke behind me that was trying to make a pass. However, I was able to hold him off as I pinned it between turns. As we went into the first pits I was feeling good and saw no reason to stop so I just went right on through and out onto the course again. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;At the end of the second loop when I got to the grass track section the same guy seemed to be behind me. On one of the turns I bobbled it and went too wide so he got by me on the inside (P15v or s, I think). As we went through the pits I made sure to obey the rules and stayed right behind or to the side of him. I noticed he was looking down a lot at his gas tank region and I wondered if he had some sort of problem. However, he didn’t stop and neither did I so I was tucked in right behind him as we hit the course again. It took me a mile or two but it finally dawned on me that he was probably checking his gas level. It didn’t even occur to me to think about gas and whether I needed to stop or not—I was having way too much fun! Since it was too late I figured I would just take my chances and see how it went. Turns out that I didn’t even need to switch to reserve, although afterwards I examined the gas level in my tank and it got pretty close.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;During the first and second loops I seemed to be stuck in a conga line a lot of the time and couldn’t go as fast as I would have liked. At the end of the second loop though I made a pass or two that put me behind the leader of the conga line who seemed to be taking it somewhat easy (an amateur according to his number plate). However, when I started to put some pressure on him he just took off. There was no way I could keep up with him. He was definitely a much faster rider than I am.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The third loop for me was my fastest and also the funnest. This is because I didn’t have anyone in front of me most of the time so I could go as fast as I wanted through the washes and single track sections. It was such a blast to rail the washes! As I traversed the off-camber rocky mountain side I heard a thumper coming up behind me. But as I cleared the steep hillclimb at the end of that section I didn’t hear him anymore and figured he must have stalled it on the hill. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;I also found I enjoyed the straight sections where you could really open it up. On the second and third loops I had a lot of fun kind of sneaking up on several guys who seemed to be taking it a little slower, probably to conserve energy, and then making a pass (or in one case, not making the pass). &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;After getting to the finish I went to the truck and saw that Aaron was not yet there. About 10 minutes later he showed up, having just finished his third loop. It turns out that after the start he realized he should have used the bathroom before the race. So, at the end of the first loop he made a pit stop in order to make a personal pit stop. Then at the end of the second loop he pitted again and got something to eat and drink. If it hadn’t been for his stops, he would have definitely finished ahead of me.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;I wore my heart rate monitor for the race and according to it I burned 2,220 calories in 2hrs 44min with an average heart rate of 153 beats per minute. Definitely a great workout!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;I just want to say thanks again to everyone who assisted with putting on this race. You did a fantastic job and your efforts are much appreciated! My son and I had a great time—can’t wait to do it again! &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Here are a few videos. The first one is an overview of the race with some helmet cam footage.&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="file://localhost/Users/nordin2/Dropbox/Public/web/Greg_Nordins_Blog/Blog/Entries/2010/10/30_What,_No_Dust_files/DSCN2691_1.jpg" length="214242" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aaron’s First Desert Dirt Bike Race</title>
      <link>file://localhost/Users/nordin2/Dropbox/Public/web/Greg_Nordins_Blog/Blog/Entries/2010/9/18_Aarons_First_Desert_Dirt_Bike_Race.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">15c4a2ff-9062-4556-b3f1-15978ba2d50e</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2010 16:36:30 -0600</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;a href=&quot;file://localhost/Users/nordin2/Dropbox/Public/web/Greg_Nordins_Blog/Blog/Entries/2010/9/18_Aarons_First_Desert_Dirt_Bike_Race_files/DSCN2322_1.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;file://localhost/Users/nordin2/Dropbox/Public/web/Greg_Nordins_Blog/Blog/Media/object001_1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float:left; padding-right:10px; padding-bottom:10px; width:216px; height:123px;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;This was my son Aaron’s (age 23) first desert race. We drove up to Snowville in northern Utah just below the Idaho border and arrived at pit row about 9:15 am. During the first hour of the drive I told Aaron about all of the lessons I’ve learned from my races, and covered what to expect at different stages of the race. However, no amount of talking can adequately prepare someone for the actual experience of doing a race.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Here is a link to a Google map that has my gps track of the race course (one loop is 30 miles and the race consisted of two loops for a total of 60 miles): &lt;a href=&quot;http://nanomicro.byu.edu/~nordin/Maps/2010-09-18%20RACE-Snowville%20with%20Aaron.html&quot;&gt;Google map&lt;/a&gt;. The start was at the little spur on the left-most part of the track and we ran it clockwise.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;It took 3 hrs 30 min to complete the race with the second loop being faster than the first because there weren’t as many people in front of us so the dust wasn’t nearly as bad and you could see the trail!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Aaron before the start:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Myself:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Here are a few videos of the start:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oTRbNP4qhSs&quot;&gt;Novices start -- shows how dusty the course was&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gqDmoVpxArk&amp;NR=1&quot;&gt;Longer video showing all of the starts&lt;/a&gt; -- the first minute or two are particularly worth watching.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Aaron and I started on the same row right next to each other (Novice, 2nd row). When it was our turn to go, Aaron pulled out ahead of me. After the second turn I put on a burst of speed and went past him. A few moments later I came to a ditch. As I finished crossing it, to my left in my peripheral vision I saw Aaron’s bike starting to pull slightly ahead of me, except it’s orientation was all wrong. The front wheel was pointing toward the sky with the whole bike slowly rotating until it was vertical, all the while being in midair. In the meantime I saw Aaron lose his grip on the handlebars and slide backwards off the seat and onto the ground. The bike continued its arc and landed on the rear fender before throwing up a giant cloud of dust as it settled into a position of minimum energy (aka, motionless flat on the ground). &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;I grabbed a handful of brake and came to a quick stop and asked Aaron if he was ok. He said he was fine as he rapidly picked himself up off the ground to get his bike and hop back on. I said something like, “Take it easy,” and sped off to continue the race. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;It turns out that my assumption as to what happened was incorrect. In my mind I flashed back to when Aaron was about 15 years old and we lived in Alabama and were riding at our favorite spot, the Kentuck ORV trails, which had lots of little jumps on various trails. After a short break with the friends we were riding with I took the lead getting back out on the trail and hit the first jump. Much to my surprise as I was in midair I felt my handle bars being jostled from the left. I looked over and there was Aaron passing me while in flight and clipping me as he went past. I just barely managed to land without wrecking while he blasted on down the trail. It was pretty funny and we’ve laughed many times since about that incident. Anyway, I immediately assumed he was trying to pull off a repeat performance but had gotten over anxious and grabbed too much throttle coming out of the ditch. It turns out that he never even saw the ditch because of the dust. In hitting it, he was thrown toward the back of the bike and inadvertently twisted the throttle while trying to hold on. His left hand grabbed for the clutch but missed as he was sliding off the back.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;It’s a little hard to see because of the background clutter, but here’s Aaron’s rear fender after we got home:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;For the next 20 minutes of the race a new pattern kept repeating itself. I would hear a 2-stroke behind me (Aaron and I both ride KTM 300’s) and it would sound just like Aaron’s bike. However, a few minutes later the bike would pass me and it would be someone else. So, I discovered that the rattle-like noise that his bike makes isn’t nearly as distinctive as I had assumed. I started to hear yet another 2 stroke behind me and thought it must be someone else just as the 3 previous ones had been. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;At that point the trail dropped down into the longest wash on the course. The dust was blinding and it was very difficult to see anything. I thought to myself that the poor person behind me must be having a particularly difficult time as I gassed my bike to get from turn to turn. I could only imagine how much dust I was kicking up. After getting out of the wash I was passed yet again by the 2 stroke behind me. I felt bad though because this time it really was Aaron!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;For hydration I had chosen not to wear my usual Camelbak backpack. Instead, I had a waist pack so as to keep weight off my back in deference to several degenerated discs in my low back. I found the waist pack to be pretty useless though because the mouthpiece was secured to the belt, rather than to a shoulder strap like for my normal backpack. The distance from waist to mouth was just too far to take my hand off the handlebar and not crash. So, I did without water. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Just after the 25 mile mark I noticed that the waist pack suddenly was much lighter. In fact, it was so light it felt like the water bladder was empty. A minute or two later I felt my body being pulled from behind at the waist down into the seat of my bike with irresistable force. I knew immediately what must have happened and came to a quick stop. Sure enough, the drinking tube had come unfastened from the belt and fallen down by the rear wheel. Due to one of the immutable laws of the universe, namely, that if anything dangles down by a wheel it will invariably get sucked into the wheel, the drinking tube was wrapped many times around the wheel hub and was stretched into a thin, tight elastic band up to the waist pack. After about 5 minutes I was able to get the drinking tube unwound from the wheel and stuff it into a pocket. Prior to being sucked into the wheel, the bite valve on the end of the tube had been pulled off by the spinning spokes and was no where to be found. Undoubtedly, this accounts for the waist pack feeling unaccountably light right before I was pulled down onto the seat. The waist pack was permanently discarded at the truck when I made it to the pits. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Here is a picture of the waist pack and tube (also note lack of bite valve on the end):&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Meanwhile, Aaron had made it back to the truck 6-7 minutes before I did. We took our sweet time gassing up, drinking lots of fluids, and devouring anything we could grab to eat before heading out for the 2nd loop. I started off in the lead and kept it at a nice sustainable pace. When I blew a corner into some trees Aaron passed me. I was able to come up close to him a little while later and I recognized something I’ve seen many times in the last half of a race: a rider who was riding slower than normal in order to conserve energy. A few minutes later he blew a corner and I passed him. I didn’t see him again until I got to the finish. As I was chugging the well-appreciated bottle of water I was handed, I looked back and saw Aaron coming into the finish about a minute and a half after I had gotten there. So, the young guy was faster on the first lap, but the old guy had a little more staying power on the last lap. In any case, we had an absolute blast doing the race together! What a memorable experience—it just doesn’t get any better than doing a race together with your son! &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Here are a few other observations/comments in no particular order:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;1. The dust was incredible. During the first lap I was amazed when I suddenly realized that I had mud in my mouth from all of the dust coming in contact with saliva. Not a pleasant discovery. I was in a quandary as to what to do with it because I just knew that if I tried to spit it out I would get it inside my helmet. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;2. It seemed like I passed the same guys over and over on the first lap. Once past them I would stall or low side it in a corner and they would all get by me and I’d have to pass them all again. I can’t count how many times this happened. I’m sure they were thinking the same thing about me—“Man, why do we have to pass this same guy over and over??”&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;3. On our ride home we started off with a few flies in the cab of our truck, which was annoying. So we’d swat them or open a window to try to get them to exit. The only trouble was, this continued for the whole 2 hours of the ride home. We must have dealt with 25 or more flies. It’s hard to believe we picked up that many in pit row. I guess that when they saw a chance to escape the ranch they took it! &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Finally, many thanks to the Buzzards and Eliason family—great job on an excellent course!&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="file://localhost/Users/nordin2/Dropbox/Public/web/Greg_Nordins_Blog/Blog/Entries/2010/9/18_Aarons_First_Desert_Dirt_Bike_Race_files/DSCN2322_1.jpg" length="236865" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mt. Timpanogos Summit Hike</title>
      <link>file://localhost/Users/nordin2/Dropbox/Public/web/Greg_Nordins_Blog/Blog/Entries/2010/8/21_Mt._Timpanogos_Summit_Hike.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">b06504b9-d107-49cd-bb72-ee41d6933e81</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2010 11:33:05 -0600</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;a href=&quot;file://localhost/Users/nordin2/Dropbox/Public/web/Greg_Nordins_Blog/Blog/Entries/2010/8/21_Mt._Timpanogos_Summit_Hike_files/DSCN2020.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;file://localhost/Users/nordin2/Dropbox/Public/web/Greg_Nordins_Blog/Blog/Media/object000_1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float:left; padding-right:10px; padding-bottom:10px; width:216px; height:123px;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;My son Aaron and I hiked the Timpooneke trail from American Fork Canyon to the summit of Mt. Timpanogos (11,750 ft). It was absolutely epic with beautiful weather and stunning views. The trail was incredible, especially at and near the summit. The last few Saturdays I’ve hiked to the top of Big Baldy (a hike I’ve done many times), Box Elder Peak (11,100 ft), and now Mt. Timpanogos. There are many other peaks nearby so I am thinking to start climbing more of them.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Aaron and I started our Mt. Timpanogos hike at 9:50 am. It took us 6 hours hiking time, with 45 minutes spent at the summit and 15 minutes chatting with the emergency response crew at Emerald Lake for a total round trip time of 7 hours. Here are a few other details:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Total distance: 14.9 miles&lt;br/&gt;Total climb elevation: 6,500 ft&lt;br/&gt;Time to summit: 3:35&lt;br/&gt;Time from summit down snowfield to Emerald Lake: 0:55&lt;br/&gt;Time from Emerald Lake back down to truck: 1:30 (we ran pretty much the whole way)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://nanomicro.byu.edu/~nordin/Maps/HI100821-Mt%20Timpanogos%20with%20Aaron.html&quot;&gt;Click here to go to a terrain map of the hike&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Pictures and a description of the hike are at this link: &lt;a href=&quot;http://web.me.com/greg.nordin/Utah_Offroad_Biking/My_Albums/Pages/Aug_21,_2010-Mt_Timpanogos_Hike.html#0&quot;&gt;8/21/10 Mt. Timpanogos Hike Photos&lt;/a&gt;. Definitely check these out!</description>
      <enclosure url="file://localhost/Users/nordin2/Dropbox/Public/web/Greg_Nordins_Blog/Blog/Entries/2010/8/21_Mt._Timpanogos_Summit_Hike_files/DSCN2020.jpg" length="172445" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
