<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="F4508815-F21A-44D6-808D-A838FFEEC6D1">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20120629" date="2012-06-29 07:23:50 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Cherry Creek Reprise II&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Friday, March 27, 2009&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;After the hill climb we forged on a little further and took a break to enjoy the views. Here is Steve getting his camera out to take a picture&#xD;&#xD;View from the trail&#xD;&#xD;Trying to decide which way to go. Straight ahead the trail ends so we decide to go left.&#xD;&#xD;We ended up running into a fair amount of snow&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;If you look closely, you can see Matt&#x2019;s jersey is ripped open in the front. He took a little dive over the handlebars in the snow...&#xD;&#xD;We found some nice single track&#xD;&#xD;But then lost it in the snow&#xD;&#xD;We finally emerged in what Matt described as the &#x201C;Shire&#x201D;&#xD;&#xD;Which included these interesting holes filled with ice&#xD;&#xD;This is Cherry Creek Reservoir. First time I&#x2019;ve been here.&#xD;&#xD;Steve took this picture while on top of the dam&#xD;&#xD;And here is the outlet at the base of the dam. Interesting seeing the ice buildup and water spraying out of holes in the outlet pipe.&#xD;&#xD;Eric getting ready to lead us back to the truck&#xD;&#xD;The trail is in the far left of the picture starting just above the seat of my bike (the one on the left)&#xD;&#xD;After a fun high speed ride down whooped out trails and a gravel road it was time to load up and head home. Here is Matt at the end of the ride. Notice the rip in his jersey reveals &#x201C;Honda&#x201D; trying to bust out. Perhaps he has a Honda in his future?&#xD;&#xD;It was another great day of riding, and an excellent workout. We rode for 4 hours and my heart rate monitor said I burned 2,550 calories. What a sport--lot&#x2019;s of fun, beautiful back country to see, great friends to ride with, and excellent exercise! &#xD;&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="27_Cherry_Creek_Reprise_II_files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="700px" height="400px"/>
</content>
