<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="F4508815-F21A-44D6-808D-A838FFEEC6D1">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20120629" date="2012-06-29 07:24:06 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;South Korea&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Sunday, May 24, 2009&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Yesterday I got back from a trip to South Korea to attend and speak at the &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.nmc2009.org/"&gt;International Workshop on Nanomechanical Cantilever Sensors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;, which was held on Jeju, an island off the south coast of the Korean peninsula. I left Sunday, May 17, at 9:30 pm, arriving Tuesday, May 19. The conference took place Wed through Friday with excursions Thursday and Friday afternoon. &#xD;&#xD;My flight itnerary took me from Salt Lake City to Los Angeles to Incheon where I had to take a bus to another airport, Gimpo, to catch a plane to Jeju. Here is my mode of transportation on the LAX to Incheon leg of the journey.&#xD;&#xD;Incheon aiport (Seoul). This is the nicest airport I&#x2019;ve been in.&#xD;&#xD;The conference was held in the Ramada hotel right on the waterfront in Jeju. Here is the inside of the hotel.&#xD;&#xD;View from the conference room we used on the 8th floor.&#xD;&#xD;Thursday&#x2019;s afternoon excursion took us to Jungmun Beach on the south side of the island. It was a rainy day so we just went on a walk. There were about 100 people who attended the workshop, with maybe 60-70 who went on the excursion.&#xD;&#xD;View of the beach. &#xD;&#xD;Before going down to the beach our path took us by this famous mailbox. Note the plaque says this is the &#x201C;Mail Box on the Hill of the First Love.&#x201D; Don&#x2019;t know what this means--there was no one to tell us the story behind the mailbox.&#xD;&#xD;On the beach with Jerry who is now on the faculty of a university in Shanghai. He used to be a postdoc in Thomas Thundat&#x2019;s group at Oak Ridge National Laboratory.&#xD;&#xD;After walking on the beach we saw some Korean surfer dudes and someone who had gathered some tasty items from the sea.&#xD;&#xD;Jeju island was formed by volcanos so there is a lot of lava rock. Here is a little further down the coast. Curious how the lava cooled into packed hexagonal columns.&#xD;&#xD;Friday afternoon&#x2019;s excursion was to Sunrise Peak on the east side of the island. The buses were going to leave at 2:00 pm from the hotel driveway. I arrived at 2:05 and found that they had already left. Since I hadn&#x2019;t been getting much exercise on the trip, I walked a few blocks away and rented a bicycle and planned to ride east along the coast. My rented bike turned out to be pretty junky--think of a heavily used, poorly maintained Walmart special. It would only shift into about half of the available gears. Nonetheless, it was nice to get back out on a bike.&#xD;&#xD;One of my stops was at a pagoda shrine. Here is one of the buildings.&#xD;&#xD;Later, I came across these boats in a small harbor. Note the string of high intensity light bulbs hanging down the center of each boat. At night from my hotel room I could see numerous bright lights far out on the ocean which I assume were boats such as these trying to attract some type of sea critter. I&#x2019;m not sure how they caught them though because I didn&#x2019;t see any nets.&#xD;&#xD;One of the places I passed was Hamdeok Beach, which was quite scenic. Note the lava rock interspersed with the sand.&#xD;&#xD;Along the way, I kept seeing these odd vehicles.&#xD;&#xD;I also noticed this business establishment with a very odd name. I think it was a restaurant. Need to work on the translation though.&#xD;&#xD;The ride was great. I went about 35 miles and saw some scenic areas as well as a lot of the rural countryside. I was favorably impressed with the country and the people and enjoyed visiting South Korea for the first time.&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="24_South_Korea_files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="700px" height="400px"/>
</content>
